<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Computer Vision | HUSMEN</title><link>https://husmen.xyz/tag/computer-vision/</link><atom:link href="https://husmen.xyz/tag/computer-vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Computer Vision</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://husmen.xyz/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Computer Vision</title><link>https://husmen.xyz/tag/computer-vision/</link></image><item><title>A Reproducible Educational Plan to Teach Mini Autonomous Race Car Programming</title><link>https://husmen.xyz/publications/racecar2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://husmen.xyz/publications/racecar2020/</guid><description>&lt;!--
&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
Click the &lt;em>Cite&lt;/em> button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
Click the &lt;em>Slides&lt;/em> button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
Supplementary notes can be added here, including [code and math](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/).
-->
&lt;p>As autonomous cars and complex features of them grow in popularity, ensuring that analyses and capabilities are reproducible and repeatable has taken on importance in education plans too. This paper describes a reproducible research plan on mini autonomous race car programming. This educational plan is designed and implemented as part of a summer internship program at Kocaeli University and it consists of theoretical courses and laboratory assignments. A literate programming approach with the Python language is used for programming the race car. To assess the educational program&amp;rsquo;s impact on the learning process and to evaluate the acceptance and satisfaction level of students, they answered an electronic questionnaire after finishing the program. According to students&amp;rsquo; feedback, the reproducible educational program is useful for learning and consolidating new concepts of mini autonomous car programming.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FourPlusOne</title><link>https://husmen.xyz/portfolio/fourplusone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://husmen.xyz/portfolio/fourplusone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Autonomous Driving System for mini vehicles (MIT-RACECAR), deployed with ROS on a Jetson TX2. More details will be added soon.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>